Prathmesh Desai

http://www.prathmeshdesai.com prathmesh.desai@uwaterloo.ca | 628.208.9633

Permanent Address: 2650 Meadow Ridge Dr, Prosper, TX, USA, 75078 Temporary Address: Unit B - 249 Albert St, Waterloo, ON, Canada, N2L 3T7

LEGAL STATUS

Citizen of Canada Permanent Resident of The United States My passion for Computer Science stems from both a desire to invent, and an immense amount of intellectual curiosity for machines. This intrigue started when my sixth grade self found out about the destructive power of rm -rf / and bash scripts. Ever since then I have continued to further my programming expertise by hacking on side-projects, freelance work, reading books, and working at rising startups.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

CANDIDATE FOR BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE Expected May 2019 | Waterloo, ON

COURSEWORK

Functional Programming
Algo. Design & Data Abstraction
Logic & Computation
Data Structures
Sequential Programs
Adv. Intro to Combinatorics
AP Computer Science (HS)

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

HTML CSS jQuery JS Python Swift Clojure SQL LISP C C++ Java

WEB SERVERS/SERVICES

Apache Nginx RESTful SOAP IIS OAuth 2.0

FRAMEWORKS

Express Jade Rails React React Native Django Meteor Angular Laravel

BACKEND TECHNOLOGIES

MongoDB Redis MySQL AWS S3 PostgreSQL GraphQL

GRAPHICS

Photoshop Illustrator InDesign Maya Blender Sketch

MISCELLANEOUS

Theatre Directing Skiing

EXPERIENCE

HORIZONS SCHOOL OF TECHNOLOGY | INSTRUCTOR &

CURRICULUM DEVELOPER

January 2017 - Present | San Francisco, CA

- Instruct students on full-stack technologies (i.e. JS/React/Redux/React Native/Node/Express/MongoDB/AWS/Redis/Mocha/Chai)
- Develop exercises, quizzes, and exams to cover course material and solidify student understanding of taught services
- Lead standup & implemented Agile project management tactics for four different project teams
- Worked on a slack bot that matches on-duty instructors and students seeking help on Slack (deployed on Heroku & uses PostgreSQL to keep track of relevant data)

FARMLOGS | SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

January 2016 - May 2016 | Ann Arbor, MI

- Maintained, tested, & added features to the FarmLogs WebApp and Static Site (using React, Jasmine, Backbone, and HTML/CSS/iQuery)
- Refactored established codebase to start using React
- Gained an in-depth understanding of d3 and used it to analyze data and create responsive, interactive charts/graphs
- Was an integral part of the Prescriptions (allow tractors to dispense appropriate amounts of Nitrogen on fields based on its' location) feature team, and participated in multiple feature specific sprints and scrum meetings

HUBDOC | SOFTWARE MARKETER & WEB DEVELOPER

May 2015 - August 2015 | Toronto, ON

- Responsible for end-to-end development of the static site
- Heavily used CSS & jQuery to implement light, creative, and responsive animations
- Learned Bootstrap responsive web design, static asset management, and efficient web performance techniques
- Lead social media marketing at Hubdoc by routinely promoting both in-house & external accounting content via Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, and email
- Wrote well-received accounting-related content (blog posts, tweets, etc.) and managed the Hubdoc Blog
- Created Python web scrapers to crawl popular accounting directories and generate tens of thousands of new leads for the sales team

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE | Cancer Research Intern

Winter 2012 - Fall 2013 | Knoxville, TN

- Worked with **Amila Orucevic** to prove that the introduction of adjuvant anti-HER2 treatment has no impact on overall survival, despite common belief
- Our research was conducted by acquiring thousands of patient records, and running Python scripts to extract relevant information to analyze